Imagine you're driving in a city with your friend.
设想一下 你正和朋友在一个城市中驾驶
You have a goal that you're trying to get to.
你有一个想去的目的地
You are sitting in the passenger seat and your friend is driving.
你是乘客 你朋友是司机
You plug that goal into Google Maps and you
你把目的地输入 Google 地图
get some route that will get you to your destination.
然后你得到一些到达目的地的路线
The driver shouldn't be concerned about the details of what the route exactly is.
司机无须关心路线精确地如何
Right, because the driver trusts that you acting, as the navigator,
是的 因为司机相信你 你作为领航员
will tell them what maneuvers they need to make and it's
将告诉你朋友该如何操作
understood that they are just responsible for executing them.
你朋友只是负责按照你的指示操作
In this situation, the responsibilities of the passenger are
这种情况下 乘客的职责
analogous to the responsibilities of a behavior planner in a self-driving car.
与无人驾驶汽车的行为规划器类似
So if you tell your friend to go left, they will do that.
所以 你告诉朋友左转 你朋友就会左转
And when you tell the driver to pass a slow vehicle,
当你告诉朋友超过前面一辆慢车的时候
the driver won't worry about whether they have enough time to do so because they
你朋友不会担心是否有时间做这个动作
will assume that you have thought about that
因为朋友相信你已经预先考虑过时间问题
and that you're confident that they can make it.
你相信朋友可以执行超车动作
But the navigator is not responsible for safety.
但是 领航员不负责安全性
If you tell the driver to get back to the left lane but there is a vehicle in the way,
如果你告诉朋友回到左边车道 但是该车道上有一辆车
you will assume that they will wait to move
你是在假定你朋友会先等待
left until there is enough room to do so safely.
等左边有了足够空档后再行动
The navigator will also tell the driver when to keep their lane and when it is
领航员也会告诉司机何时保持车道 何时转弯
time to turn or change lanes or maybe adjust the speed.
何时换道或者改变速度
And finally, once you're arrived at your destination,
最后 当你们到达目的地后
you will tell the driver to stop.
你会指示朋友停车
So, to summarize, the behavior planner is
现在 我们总结一下 行为规划器目前是个黑盒子
currently a black box which takes as input a map of the world,
它把地图数据作为输入
a route to the destinations,
同时输入的还有到目的地的路线
and predictions about what other static and dynamic obstacles are likely to do,
它的输入还包括其他静态或者动态障碍物的下一步可能动向
and it produces as output a adjusted maneuver for the vehicle which
然后规划器生成车辆的下一个动作
the trajectory planner is responsible for reaching collision-free, smooth, and safe.
对于此动作 会由轨迹规划器负责平滑、安全、无碰撞地执行
The goal of this lesson is to open up
本课程的目的是打开这个黑盒子
this black box and learn how to implement a behavior planner.
告诉大家如何实现一个行为规划器
So the responsibilities of
行为模块的职责
the behavior module are to suggest maneuvers which are feasible,
是提出一些建议动作
as safe as possible, legal, and efficient.
这些动作应该是可行的、最安全的、不会违规的、高效的
What the behavior planner is not responsible
行为模块不负责动作执行的细节
for are execution details and collision avoidance.
也不负责进行碰撞检测
The approach to behavior planning we are going to teach in
本课程中要讲的行为规划算法
this lesson is the same one used by most of the vehicles,
与绝大多数车辆上使用的相同
including the winning one in the DARPA Urban Challenge.
包括 DARPA 都市挑战赛上的优胜车 也是使用此方法
In fact, it's the approach to
实际上 奔驰公司在 Bertha Benz Drive 系列车型上
behavior planning that Mercedes used in their Bertha Benz Drive,
也是使用此方法来做行为规划
which you can see is capable of handling
大家也许知道 那个车型已经具备应付复杂环境的能力
complex traffic situations like navigating intersections and dense urban traffic.
包括绕过交叉路口和城市车流量大的道路
And while this approach is not necessarily the most common anymore,
然而 此方法并不是最流行的方法
for reasons we will discuss later,
其原因我们后面会讲到
it is widely known in the field and it does give
但是 它在业界却是非常知名的
a very high-level understanding of what is going on in a behavior planner.
通过学习此方法 大家可以一窥行为规划的全貌